اَلْحَمْدُ لله ، وَالصَّلَاةُ وَالسَّلَامُ عَلى سَيِّدِنَا محمد وَعَلَى اَلِهِ وَصَحْبِهِ وَسَلِّمْ
One story that was mentioned to us in Qur'an, gives us an impression about the Hawariyyeen(حواريّين).
And the Hawariyyeen(حواريّين) are the Sahabah(صحابه) of Sayidina Eesa(سيدنا عيسى).
The followers or the companions of Sayidina Muhammadﷺ were called Sahabah(صحابه).
The Companions of Sayidina Eesa عليه السلام were called Al-Hawariyyeen(الحواريّين).
In English; The disciples.
These Ayaat(آيات) are in Surat ul Maidah(سورةالمائدة).
And Al-Maidah(المائدة) is named after these Ayaat(آيات); because Al-Maidah(المائدة) means; a table.
Allahسُبحانه وتعالى says;
إِذْ قَالَ الْحَوَارِيُّونَ يَا عِيسَى ابْنَ مَرْيَمَ هَلْ يَسْتَطِيعُ رَبُّكَ أَن يُنَزِّلَ عَلَيْنَا مَائِدَةً مِّنَ السَّمَاءِ ۖ
Remember! When Al-Hawariyyeen(الحواريّين); The disciples said, Oh Eesa(عيسى)! And Eesa(عيسى) is Jesus.
And by the way, the name Eesa(عيسى) is closer to the right pronunciation of his real name, than Jesus is.
Because, in the Aramaic language of Sayidina Eesa(سيدنا عيسى) and the people of Sayidina Eesa(سيدنا عيسى), the letter ''J'' did not exist.
So the name Jesus isn't truly his name.
His name is Eesa(عيسى) or at least it's a closer pronunciation of the name of Sayidina Eesa عليه السلام.
But in English; now it's called Jesus.
They said; Can your Lord send down to us a table spread with food from heaven?
So the companions, Al-Hawariyyeen(الحواريّين), and we'll use the name Al-Hawariyyeen(الحواريّين) from now on, the disciples.
Al-Hawariyyeen(الحواريّين); they came to Sayidina Eesa عليه السلام, and they said; Can your Lord send us a table?
Now, if this question means; Is Allah able to do so?
Then this is Kuffr(كفر).
What do you mean, Allah is not able to bring down a table from the sky?
You're doubting the ability of Allahسُبحانه وتعالى.
Can Allah bring down the table? Of course, Allah can.
Is that the meaning they intended?
According to some scholars; yes, but the majority say; that's not what they intended.
Especially, when we know in Qur'an Allahسُبحانه وتعالى says about Al-Hawariyyeen(الحواريّين).
Sayidina Eesa عليه السلام said;
مَنْ أَنصَارِي إِلَى اللَّهِ ۖ
Who are my supporters in the sake of Allah?
قَالَ الْحَوَارِيُّونَ نَحْنُ أَنصَارُ اللَّهِ
The Hawariyyeen(حواريّين) said; we are going to be the ones who will give victory to the religion of Allah.
آمَنَّا بِاللَّهِ وَاشْهَدْ بِأَنَّا مُسْلِمُونَ۝
We believed in Allah and be a witness that we are Muslims.
So this Ayah(آية) gives us an indication that, the that the followers of Sayidina Eesa(سيدنا عيسى) were firm believers, who believed in him,
and believed in Allahسُبحانه وتعالى, and believed in Islam.
So we cannot expect from them to come to Eesa(عيسى) and ask him;
Can Allah bring down a table, as if they're questioning the ability of Allah to do so.
So what does this Ayah(آية) means?
The scholars say that, what they meant by this question is; is it possible for you to ask Allah to bring down a table for us?
Can Allah bring down a table?
So they're asking him; can Allah do this for us?
Is it something that you can ask Allah to do for us?
You get the meaning.
There are two different things.
But again; it's not something that the Sahabah(صحابه) of Rasool Allah ﷺ did.
The followers of Muhammadﷺ never requested Allahسُبحانه وتعالى to send down a miracle.
Never!
Never did any one of the companions; The Sahabahرضى الله عنهم come to Rasool Allah ﷺ and say; Perform for us a miracle; Never!
They never did it.
So the Hawariyyeen(حواريّين); they did come to Eesa(عيسى), and they asked for a miracle.
Sayidina Eesa عليه السلام said;
اتَّقُوا اللَّهَ
Fear Allahسُبحانه وتعالى.
Why are you asking me to do so?
اتَّقُوا اللَّهَ إِن كُنتُم مُّؤْمِنِينَ۝
Fear Allah, if you are indeed believer.
They gave their justifications.
They said;
قَالُواْ نُرِيدُ أَن نَّأْكُلَ مِنْهَا
They said; We wish to eat, thereof.
They might have been very hungry, and they wanted Rizq(رزق) from Allahسُبحانه وتعالى.
And it's okay to ask for Rizq(رزق) from Allah.
وَتَطْمَئِنَّ قُلُوبُنَا
And to satisfy our hearts.
When we see miracle, it will satisfy our hearts.
It will make our Eeman(ايمان); firmer and stronger.
So that's number two.
وَنَعْلَمَ أَن قَدْ صَدَقْتَنَا
And to know that you have indeed told us the truth.
And again; you can see here a little bit of a difference again between the Sahabah(صحابه) of Muhammadﷺ and Hawariyyeen(حواريّين).
The are saying; we want to see this, to make sure that you have told us the truth.
وَنَكُونَ عَلَيْهَا مِنَ ٱلشَّٰهِدِينَ۝
And that, we ourselves be its witnesses.
Now even though, they made this the last justification.
It should have been the first; because it has the strongest foundation.
They said; we want to be witnesses.
In other words, they're asking Sayidina Eesa(سيدنا عيسى) to perform this miracles in front of their eyes,
so that, they can be witnesses in front of mankind; to say that we have seen this miracle with our eyes.
So when they go in Da'wah(دعوة), and when they go to convey the message of Allahسُبحانه وتعالى;
they can tell the people that, we have seen Eesa Ibn Maryam(عيسى ابن مريم) performed this miracle in front of our eyes;
وَنَكُونَ عَلَيْهَا مِنَ ٱلشَّٰهِدِينَ۝
We will witness that, we will be witnesses in front of mankind.
They convinced Sayidina Eesa عليه السلام with the validity of their request.
Jesus, son of Mary said;
قَالَ عِيسَى ابْنُ مَرْيَمَ اللَّهُمَّ رَبَّنَا أَنزِلْ عَلَيْنَا مَائِدَةً مِّنَ السَّمَاءِ تَكُونُ لَنَا عِيدًا لِّأَوَّلِنَا وَآخِررِنَا
Eesa(عيسى); Jesus; son of Mary said;
Oh Allah, our Lord! Send us from the heaven a table spread with food.
Now, when Sayidina Eesa عليه السلام made a Dua(دُعَا), and he was telling Allahسُبحانه وتعالى, why he wants the table.
He did not use the same four justifications that Al-Hawariyyeen(الحواريّين) used.
But he said;
تَكُونُ لَنَا عِيدًا لِّأَوَّلِنَا وَآخِرِنَا
Maybe for us a festival for the first and the last of us.
Eesa(عيسى) said; send down this table.
So that number one; it would be Eid(عيد) for us.
What does Eid(عيد) mean?
Eid(عيد) is a festival; but if we look at the linguistic meaning of the word Eid(عيد); Min Ya'ud(من يعود).
Eid(عيد) in Arabic; it would mean; something that returns.
It returns again and again.
It would mean; something that is good.
So why do we say Eid(عيد) a celebration?
Because it's something that comes on a yearly basis like, Eid-ul-Fitr(عيدالفطر) and Eid-ul-Adha(عيدالاضحى),
or it comes on a weekly basis like, Al-Jumu'ah(جُمعه).
And it's a moment of celebration, a good moment, a pleasurable moment.
So we wanted to come again and again.
Sayidina Eesa عليه السلام wanted this to be Eid(عيد) for them.
So that, they would remember the blessing of Allahسُبحانه وتعالى.
Just as Eid-ul-Fitr(عيدالفطر) for example, is a celebration for us
because we have completed the fasting of the month of Ramadan(رمضان), and now we are breaking our fast.
And that's why, Rasool Allah ﷺ says;
لصائم فرحتان
For the person who's fasting has two moments of happiness; once when they break their fasting,
and once on the day of judgment when they see the reward of their fasting.
Sayidina Eesa(سيدنا عيسى) said; we want this to be Eid(عيد) for us.
And then he said;
وَآيَةً مِّنكَ ۖ
It will be assigned from You; a miracle.
وَارْزُقْنَا وَأَنتَ خَيْرُ الرَّازِقِينَ۝
Provide for us sustenance; You Are the best of Sustainers.
Al-Hawariyyeen(الحواريّين), they said;
Number one;
What?
We want to eat.
Sayidina Eesa(سيدنا عيسى) made it the last reason.
وَارْزُقْنَا
Give us Rizq(رزق).
And Sayidina Eesa(سيدنا عيسى) did not limited to food.
He did not say; Oh Allah! Give us this table to be food for us.
Because food is only a very small part of Rizq(رزق).
And Eesa(عيسى) made a comprehensive, and we learned from the Adiya(ادعیا) of the Ambiyaa(أنبِيَاء); he made this comprehensive and said; Oh Allah! Give us Rizq(رزق).
Not only limited to food on a table; give us Rizq(رزق).
And Rizq(رزق) would include food, wealth, anything that you own, anything that you have.
Knowledge is also a form of Rizq(رزق); all of this is a Rizq(رزق) from Allahسُبحانه وتعالى.
وَارْزُقْنَا وَأَنتَ خَيْرُ الرَّازِقِينَ۝
Oh Allah! Give us and You Are the best of Providers.
Allahسُبحانه وتعالى said;
قَالَ ٱللَّهُ إِنِّى مُنَزِّلُهَا عَلَيْكُمْ ۖ
Allah said; I am going to send it down unto you; I will send it down.
But Allahسُبحانه وتعالى says;
فَمَن يَكْفُرْ بَعْدُ مِنكُمْ فَإِنِّىٓ أُعَذِّبُهُۥ عَذَابًا لَّآ أُعَذِّبُهُۥٓ أَحَدًا مِّنَ ٱلْعَٰلَمِينَ۝
Allah says; I'm going to send it down unto you;
but if any of you after that disbelieves; then I will punish him with a torment such as, I have not inflicted on anyone among all the world.
When you ask for an Ayah(آية); when you ask for a miracle, and the miracle is performed, and then you disbelieve,
it is worse than disbelieving without seeing a miracle.
Why?
Because you have asked Allah to provide you with a proof, and He provided you with the proof; nevertheless, you refused.
And that's why, the more a person knows; the more a person is knowledgeable; the more responsible they become.
I mean, the responsibility on the scholar is greater than the responsibility on the layman, who has very limited information.
Why?
Because the scholar now, has many of the Ayaat(آيات) of Allah with him; which makes it, the greater obligation.
And that's why, we know that the first three whom will be burnt in hellfire are who?
The scholar, and the Shaheed(شَهِيد), and who?
And the man who spent a lot of money.
Why?
Because these are people who had signs of Allahسُبحانه وتعالى, had Ni'mah(نِعْمَة) from Allahسُبحانه وتعالى, and then they didn't use it right.
The scholar used it to show off.
And the Shaheed(شَهِيد) was fighting not for the sake of Allah, but was fighting for what?
For fame.
And then the other person was being generous; just to show the person; the people that he is generous.
When you have seen the sign from Allahسُبحانه وتعالى; the obligation becomes greater.
This is the story of Al-Maidah(المائدة), and most of the scholars agreed that the Maidah(مائدة) was sent down.
Now, in some of the books of Tafseer(تفسير); the old books of Tafseer(تفسير);
they mentioned, for example; the type of food that came down.
They said; it was a fish that came down from the sky.
And the fish was surrounded by five loaves of bread.
One bread had olives, and one bread had cheese, and Subhan Allah(سُبْحان الله)! This is;
عِلمٍ لا يَنفَع
This is knowledge that does not benefit.
And as the tradition, that we have been following throughout the series of the lives of the Prophet, that we stay away from;
عِلمٍ لا يَنفَع
We stay away from the things that are not verified.
If something is not confirmed by the Ayah(آية) of Qur'an or the Hadith(حديث); we stay away from it.
What's the use of knowing, whether it was fish or meat or olives or bread?
What is the benefit?
Qur'an did not mentioned it, because there is no use to knowing such information.
And that is;
ترف علم
That is luxury of knowledge.
And that is;
عِلمٍ لا يَنفَع
Knowledge that does not benefit.
It is knowledge that would not make you ignorant if you don't know it; and knowledge that will not make you knowledgeable if you do know it.
And there's a lot of stories that were attributed to Sayidina Eesa(سيدنا عيسى) that would fall under this category, and we're going to stay away from all of them.
If it does not confirmed strongly by the Ayah(آية) of Qur'an or the Hadith(حديث); then it's better to refrain from it.
Why?
Because Allahسُبحانه وتعالى Would not hide away from us knowledge, if it's beneficial for us, if it's going to provide us with; Huda(هدى); guidance.
The Yahood(يهود) in the time of Sayidina Eesa عليه السلام; they rejected the message of Eesa(عيسى), and a very small group believed in him.
And these were Al-Hawariyyeen(الحواريّين).
The rest of the community; whether it was the community itself, which were the jews, or the authorities, which were the Romans; they rejected the message of Eesaعليه السلام.
The Jews plotted against Eesa(عيسى), and they conspired against him, with the government.
They made a plot with the government, to assassinate and get rid of Sayidina Eesa(سيدنا عيسى).
And the Roman authorities joined with the Yahood(يهود) in that conspiracy.
The Yahood(يهود) are the ones who instigated it and then the Jews actually use the Romans to perform that plot against Sayidina Eesa(سيدنا عيسى).
And the decree was issued that, Sayidina Eesa عليه السلام should be executed in public, by carrying him over the cross, and putting a crown over his head.
Not the crown of gold or silver; but thorns.
And to nail him to the cross, and let him bleed till death.
And that was a very gruesome way of execution that they used to do.
They would make a cross out of wood.
And then, they would nail the hands and the feet to the cross.
They would hit nails in the hands, and hang you on the cross and you would bleed from this injury from your feet and your hands until you die.
And you could stay for hours and hours in the sun on that cross; dying a very slow death.
So it was a very gruesome way of execution.
So the law has been decreed that, Sayidina Eesa عليه السلام should be executed.
We don't know the exact details of what happened.
But there is a narration by Ibn Abbas(إبن عباس) and again; I'm not sure of the authenticity of this narration.
So we don't approve it or disapprove it.
But it says that Sayidina Eesa عليه السلام ran into a room where all of his Hawariyyeen(حواريّين) were sitting.
And then he told them; who will volunteer to sacrifice their life for me.
One of the young, Hawariyyeen(حواريّين) raised up his hand and said; I will!
Eesaعليه السلام asked another time; he's the only one who responded, he asked for a third time; that young man was the only one who responded.
And this sacrifice is similar to what Ali Ibn Abi Talib(علي ابن ابي طالب) did, when Rasool Allah ﷺ was in Al-Hijrah(هجرة).
And incidentally enough, Subhan Allah(سُبْحان الله)! Ali Ibn Abi Talib(علي ابن ابي طالب) was young at that time.
This young man came out, and Allahسُبحانه وتعالى put on him the resemblance of Sayidina Eesa عليه السلام.
And he was the one who was crucified.
Allahسُبحانه وتعالى opened for Eesa(عيسى) a window in the roof, and he was picked up by the angels safely and elevated to the heavens.
This is one story.
The other story is that, Allahسُبحانه وتعالى put the resemblance on one of the Jews who was an enemy of Sayidina Eesa(سيدنا عيسى).
So Allah put the resemblance on him, and he was the one who was hanged on the cross.
Regardless of who was hanged on the cross; it is not Eesa Ibn Maryam(عيسى ابن مريم).
That is, what we are sure about; It was not Eesa Ibn Maryam(عيسى ابن مريم).
And Allahسُبحانه وتعالى says in Surat Al-Imran(آلعمران);
وَمَكَرُواْ وَمَكَرَ ٱللَّهُ ۖ وَٱللَّهُ خَيْرُ ٱلْمَٰكِرِينَ۝
And they disbelievers plotted to kill Eesa(عيسى), and Allah plotted too; and Allah Is the best of those, who plot.
Makar(مَكَر) means; when you plan in secret; when you're whispering; hiding in a room making a plan, that is called Makar(مَكَر).
They think that they are doing Makar(مَكَر).
They think that they're concealing their plan, and nobody knows their plan.
But there is one who knows their plan, and that is Allahسُبحانه وتعالى.
Allah knows their plan so Allah is;
خَيْرُ ٱلْمَٰكِرِينَ۝
Allah Is the best of plotters.
Because Allah; when He makes His plan; His plan can be secret and concealed, if Allah doesn't want anybody to know it.
So they made their plan; but Allah made His plan.
And the plan of Allahسُبحانه وتعالى is what we'll go through.
إِذْ قَالَ اللَّهُ يَا عِيسَىٰ إِنِّي مُتَوَفِّيكَ
Allahسُبحانه وتعالى said; Oh Eesa(عيسى)! I Will take you.
مُتَوَفِّيكَ
Many who read this Ayah(آية) think that Eesa Ibn Maryam(عيسى ابن مريم) died.
Why?
Because the word Wafa(وَفَى) in Arabic means, death.
Tuwuffi(تُوَفِّىْ) means; he died.
Wafa(وَفَى) is death.
So, when Allah says;
إِنِّي مُتَوَفِّيكَ
When people read this, they think that Allah Is telling Eesa Ibn Maryam(عيسى ابن مريم) that; I Will make you die.
But that is caused because of not knowing the meanings of words, and not knowing the original meaning of a word.
It is true that, in the Arabic language of today and the Arabic language of yesterday; the word Mutawaffik(مُتَوَفِّيكَ) can mean death.
But it also has other meanings.
Allahسُبحانه وتعالى refer to sleep as Wafa(وَفَى).
So what does it mean?
Does it mean death, or does it mean sleep?
The word Wafa(وَفَى) also has another third meaning, and that is; to take something completely.
وفيه الاجر
When you say;
Means pay him in full.
Over here the word Wafa(وَفَى) means; Allah's telling Eesa Ibn Maryam(عيسى ابن مريم); I Am going to take you in full, without any single injury.
You are going to be taken entirely.
You're not going to be harmed at all.
So Allahسُبحانه وتعالى Is not going to take your soul alone.
Nor Is Allahسُبحانه وتعالى going to take your body alone.
Allah Is going to take your soul and your body intact without any injury or harm.
That is what the word, Mutawaffika(مُتَوَفِّيكَ) means in this Ayah(آية).
And this is actually the original meaning of the word Wafa(وَفَى).
When we use Wafa(وَفَى) for death, or when we use it for sleeping;
we're using secondary meanings of the word, but the original meaning is; something in its entirety or completely.
And that's why, the word absolutely fits; The meaning which we want to get from the Ayah(آية);
that the Yahood(يهود) were not able to harm Eesa Ibn Maryam(عيسى ابن مريم).
وَرَافِعُكَ إِلَيَّ
And I Will elevate you to me.
وَمُطَهِّرُكَ مِنَ الَّذِينَ كَفَرُوا
And I Will purify you and clear you, of those who disbelieve.
I Will clear you and purify you; take you away from all of this impurity; all of this Najasah(نجاسة); all of this Rijs(رجس);
this environment that you're living in, I Will take you away from it.
Now just to confirm the meaning further, we'll read Ayaat(آيات) from Surat Al-Nisa(سورت النساء), Allahسُبحانه وتعالى says;
and these Ayaat(آيات) are talking about Al-Yahood(اليهود).
Because of their breaking the covenant, and of their rejection of the Ayaat(آيات) of Allah, and of their killing the prophets unjustly,
and of their saying; our hearts are wrapped,
may Allah Has set a seal upon their hearts, because of their disbelief, so they believe not but a little.
And because of their disbelief and uttering against Maryam(مريم) a grave false charge,
and because of their saying in boast; We killed Messiah, Eesa(عيسى) the son of Mary, the Messenger of Allah.
Allahسُبحانه وتعالى says; But they killed him not, nor crucified Him, but the resemblance of Eesa(عيسى) was put over another man.
And those who differ therein are full of doubts.
They have no certain knowledge; they follow nothing but conjecture.
For surely they killed him not but Allah raised him up unto himself.
And Allah is ever All Powerful, All Wise.
And Subhan Allah(سُبْحان الله)! When you read the Ayaat(آيات) of Qur'an, and you look deeply into the words.
Subhan Allah(سُبْحان الله)! You find the miracle of Qur'an.
Allahسُبحانه وتعالى said in this issue in particular, in the issue of the crucifixion, and the killing of Eesa(عيسى), Allahسُبحانه وتعالى Is saying that;
they're following nothing but doubts.
If you go back to the Bible, and you look at the evidences that are used to prove that Eesa(عيسى) was crucified,
and that he was killed, and that he was raised up from the dead; you find that all of those evidences are doubtful.
And Allahسُبحانه وتعالى summed it all in one word and Allahسُبحانه وتعالى says;
إِن يَتَّبِعُونَ إِلَّا الظَّنَّ ۖ
They are following doubts; Shak(شك).
Shak(شك) is doubtful, conjecture, there is no firm substantial evidence to prove the point.
The life of Sayidina Eesa عليه السلام is not over.
He's alive now.
And the rest of his life is in the future.
But we're not going to talk about it now.
We'll keep it to the series about Al Akhirah(الآخرة) which we're going to start talking about In Sha' Allah(ان شاء الله) next Saturday.
We started already with Al Akhirah(الآخرة) on Ramadan(رمضان), and we're going to continue In Sha' Allah(ان شاء الله) next Saturday.
So we'll reserve the part about the Second Coming back of Eesa(عيسى) until, we talk about Alamat As-Sa'ah(علامت السّآئه).
But up to this point, we are done with the history of the Ambiyaa(أنبِيَاء); we're done with the past part of the Ambiyaa(أنبِيَاء) of Allahسُبحانه وتعالى.
Now, a few points that we will close with, in regards the Ambiyaa(أنبِيَاء) of Allahسُبحانه وتعالى.
First of all; humanity and mankind; they need the Ambiyaa(أنبِيَاء) of Allah.
Mankind; they cannot live and survive without the Rusul(رُسُل), without the Ambiyaa(أنبِيَاء), without the messengers.
And I want to read to you some of the words of Ibn Al Qayyimرَحْمَةُ الله عَلَيه in this regards.
He says;
فإنه لا سبيل إلى السعادة والفلاح في الدنيا، ولا في الآخرة إلا على أيدي الرسل،
ولا سبيلَ إلى معرفة الطيب والخبيث على التفصيل إلا مِن جهتهم، ولا يُنال رضا الله البتة إلا على أيديهم،
فالطَّيِّب من الأعمال والأقوال والأخلاق، ليس إلا هديهم وما جاؤوا به،
فهم الميزانُ الراجح الذي على أقوالهم وأخلاقهم تُوزن الأخلاق والأعمال،
وبمتابعتهم يتميز أهل الضلال
Ibn Al-Qayyim(إبنِ ألقَيِّم) says; There is no way to success and happiness in this world or in Akhirah(آخرة); except through the messengers.
And there is no way to know the difference between good and evil; except through the messengers.
And there is no way to receive the pleasure of Allahسُبحانه وتعالى; except through the messengers.
And then he says; They are the standard in their words and their actions.
They are the standard, they are the criteria.
And without the Ambiyaa(أنبِيَاء) of Allahسُبحانه وتعالى; our spirits and our bodies will be dead.
When we say this; we don't only mean that, it is important for us to learn about the Ambiyaa(أنبِيَاء) of Allahسُبحانه وتعالى.
But is meant is that, the Ambiyaa(أنبِيَاء) of Allahسُبحانه وتعالى should be our guidance in everything that we do, in every aspect of our life.
And that would lead to number two.
Number two is; there's no way for us, to know and learn the guidance of the Ambiyaa(أنبِيَاء) except through; the Ayaat(آيات) of Qur'an.
There is no other way.
Where are you going to learn about the guidance of the Ambiyaa(أنبِيَاء)?
Where?
What other sources will you go back to?
Historical books?
History was not recorded yet.
Are you going to go back to the Bible?
Well let's look for example, at some of the references that were made in the Bible about the Ambiyaa(أنبِيَاء) of Allahسُبحانه وتعالى
to see if we can use it as a credible source.
The Bible says about Nuh(نوح), and these by the way, all of these verses that I will read are from the Old Testament which is part of the Jews.
Now this is talking about Nuh(نوح).
Noah; a man of the soil, proceeded to plant a vine yard.
When he drank some of its wine; he became drunk, and lay uncovered inside his tent.
Ham; the father of the father of Can'an saw his father's nakedness, and told his two brothers outside.
But Chen and Japheth took a garment and laid it across their shoulders.
Then they walked in backward and covered their father's nakedness.
Their faces were turned the other way, so that they would not see their father's nakedness.
When Noah awoke from his wine, and found out what his youngest son has done to him.
He said; Cursed be Can'an, the lowest of slaves, will he be to his brothers.
And this is in Genesis 920.
About Sayidina Ibrahimعليه السلام Exodus 31, verse one.
It mentions that Ibrahim(اِبْراهِيْم), used his wife Sarah(ساره) to go to the king of Egypt, so that he can gain some material gains.
So he sent his wife to stay with the king, so that he can get sheep, and animals, and cattle and go away with it.
Sayidina Ibrahim(اِبْراهِيْم) is selling his wife for sheep.
This is in Exodus 32 verse one; Sayidina Lutعليه السلام,
and Subhan Allah(سُبْحان الله)! I know that all of you feel uncomfortable hearing this inside the Masjid(مسجد).
Sayidina Lutعليه السلام; It says Lut(لوط), Lot and his two daughters left Zoar and settled in the mountains, for he was afraid to stay in Zoar.
He and his two daughters lived in a cave.
One day, the older daughter said to the younger; our Father is old, and there is no man around here to lie with us, as is the custom all over the earth.
Let's get our father to drink wine, and then lay with him and preserve our family line through our father.
That night they got their father to drink wine and the older daughter went in and lay with him.
He was not aware of it, when she lay down or when she got up.
The next day, the older daughter said to the younger; last night I lay with my father.
Let's get him to drink wine again tonight, and you go in and lie with him, so we can preserve our family line through our father.
And you can see of the mentality of the Yahood(يهود), the issue of preserving line and seed.
It's all talking about seed, and how to preserve our seed.
So they got their father to drink wine that night also, and the younger daughter went and lay with him.
Again, he was not aware of it, when she lay down or when she got up.
So both of Lot's daughters became pregnant by their father.
The older daughter had a son, and she named him Moab.
He is the father of the Moabites of today.
The younger daughter also had a son, and she named him; Bin Ami.
He is the father of the Ammonites of today.
See how the Yahood(يهود) are using this, to discredit the other races of the world.
They're using the Ambiyaa(أنبِيَاء) of Allahسُبحانه وتعالى as a tool to get away with lowering the other races of the earth.
And they even accuse Ibrahim عليه السّلام of having an illegitimate son which is; Ismail(اِسْماعِيْل).
By the way, when we're talking about Sayidina Lut(سيدنا لوط); and they accused him of adultery and fornication.
Subhan Allah(سُبْحان الله)! How could you say this about the Nabi(نَبِي) of Allahسُبحانه وتعالى who gave up his whole life;
calling for people to be moral; spending his life to teach the people morality.
And then you accused him of just a horrendous crime.
With Yaqoobعليه السلام; it says also in the Old Testament; that he stole sheep and goats from his father in law and ran away with them.
With Dawoodعليه السلام; and this story of about Dawood(داؤد) is really ridiculous.
In the spring, at the time when the Kings go off to war; David sent Joab out with the king's men, and the whole Israelite army.
They destroyed the Ammonites and besieged Rabba, but David remained in Jerusalem.
One evening, David got up from his bed and walked around on the roof of the palace.
From the roof, he saw a woman bathing.
The woman was very beautiful and David sent someone to find out about her.
The man said; Isn't this Bathsheba, the daughter of Iliam and the wife of Uriah of the Hittite.
Then David sent the messengers to get her.
She came to him, and he slept with her.
Now the story is long, but what happened is; this man was the leader of the armies of Sayidina Dawood(سيدناداؤد), as they claim.
When David saw how beautiful his wife was.
He slept with the wife, and then he made a plan to kill her husband, so he can take her, over.
And then it says that; but the thing David has done displeased the Lord.
With Sayidina Sulaimanعليه السلام; King Solomon, and this is in Kings 11 one, King Solomon, however, Loves many foreign woman besides Pharaoh's daughter.
And it mentions, how many woman he loved here, it says.
Nevertheless, Solomon held fast to them, in love.
He had 700 wives of royal birth, and 300 concubines, and his wives led him astray.
As Solomon grew old, his wives turned his heart after other gods, and was not fully devoted to the Lord, his God.
He followed Ashtoreth; the goddess of the Sidonians and Molech; the testable god of the Ammonites.
So Solomon did evil in the eyes of the Lord.
Anyway, so you can see that here Sayidina Sulaimanعليه السلام; as they accuse him.
In the end of his life; he started worshipping idols, and died as a Murtadd(مُرتَد).
Now, these stories that are mentioned about the Ambiyaa(أنبِيَاء) of Allahسُبحانه وتعالى; don't think that this has happened haphazardly.
There was a goal and an objective of degrading the Ambiyaa(أنبِيَاء) of Allahسُبحانه وتعالى.
When the Ambiyaa(أنبِيَاء) of Allahسُبحانه وتعالى were degraded, and they were discredited, and they lost a credibility,
then the people don't have to follow them, anymore.
So the Sunnah(سنة) of the Ambiyaa(أنبِيَاء) of Allahسُبحانه وتعالى is destroyed.
And that is the plan, that the Yahood(يهود) have done against the Ambiyaa(أنبِيَاء) of Allahسُبحانه وتعالى.
And they attempted to do that with Eesa(عيسى) and they attempted to do that to Muhammadﷺ.
These are things mentioned in a book, that is acceptable by the Yahood(يهود), and the Nasara(نصارى).
Even though, it is the Jews, who made all of these claims.
Because, all of this which I read was in the Old Testament.
But the Christians are not innocent, because they still believe in this book as theirs.
They believe in the Old Testament that it is the word of God; and they still follow it.
And this shows you, how the Yahood(يهود) would have been able to mislead the nation of the Nasara(نصارى) after them; by discrediting the Ambiyaa(أنبِيَاء) of Allahسُبحانه وتعالى.
When the Ambiyaa(أنبِيَاء) of Allahسُبحانه وتعالى are discredited; that completely throws them out of our respect; so we don't take them as role models anymore.
I mean, imagine! Would you accept one of these people to be a teacher for your child?
Would you accept a person with such manners and behavior to be a teacher of your child?
I mean, now we're living in America; with the present laws of the United States; which we as Muslims considered to be very liberal.
With the existing laws of the United States; if these men, did these things, which I listed to you; they would all be in jail now.
They would all be in jail.
If the President of the United States, or a member of Congress, or a person in public office does such a thing;
stealing the cattle of your father in law, or doing such things, or getting rid of your army general; killing him, so that you can take over his wife,
this is something that will be unacceptable and immediately you would be thrown in jail.
If we cannot trust such people to teach our children, or to lead us, or to be the president, or to be in public office; how can we trust them with our souls?
How can we trust them with their souls.?
That's why, humanity has no hope.
Mankind has no hope, except by following the way of the Ambiyaa(أنبِيَاء) of Allahسُبحانه وتعالى as taught in Qur'an.
That's the only credible reference to learn about the Ambiyaa(أنبِيَاء) of Allahسُبحانه وتعالى.
Because, I mean, if you were a Christian or a Jew; you would not want your children to read this.
You as adults were not comfortable with hearing this.
Number three; disbelieving in one of the Ambiyaa(أنبِيَاء) is equivalent to disbelieving in, all of them.
Disbelieving in one messenger, is equivalent to disbelieving in all of them.
Allahسُبحانه وتعالى says in Surat un-Nisa'(سورةالنّساء);
إِنَّ الَّذِينَ يَكْفُرُونَ بِاللَّهِ وَرُسُلِهِ
The ones, who disbelieve in Allah and His messengers;
وَيُرِيدُونَ أَن يُفَرِّقُوا بَيْنَ اللَّهِ وَرُسُلِهِ
And wish to make distinction between Allah and His messengers.
What does it mean making a distinction between Allah and His messengers, is explained next.
وَيَقُولُونَ نُؤْمِنُ بِبَعْضٍ وَنَكْفُرُ بِبَعْضٍ
By saying; we believe in some but reject others.
Allah is saying; The ones who disbelieve in Allah and His messengers; by separating between Allah and His messengers.
How do they separate between Allah and His messengers?
They say we believe in some, and we reject some.
Allahسُبحانه وتعالى Is telling you; These are my messengers, I chose them.
These are mine; These are the ones who might send to the world.
And then you come and say; No! I'm going to accept you, but I'm not going to accept you.
You're separating between them and Allah.
Allah says; These are my Ambiyaa(أنبِيَاء).
I'm The One, Who sent them to you.
And you say; No! I'm going to accept Jesus, But I'm not going to accept Muhammadﷺ.
I'm going to accept Musa(موسى), but I'm not going to accept Eesa(عيسى).
Allahسُبحانه وتعالى; what does he call this?
Allahسُبحانه وتعالى says about this;
وَيُرِيدُونَ أَن يَتَّخِذُوا بَيْنَ ذَٰلِكَ سَبِيلًا۝ أُولَٰئِكَ هُمُ الْكَافِرُونَ حَقًّا ۚ
Allah says; They are in true disbelievers; They are truly disbelievers.
If you disbelieve in one of the Ambiyaa(أنبِيَاء) of Allahسُبحانه وتعالى; it is as if you have rejected them all.
Allahسُبحانه وتعالى says in Surat Ash-Shu'ra'(سورت الشُّعراء);
كَذَّبَتْ قَوْمُ نُوحٍ الْمُرْسَلِينَ۝
The people of Nuh(نوح) have disbelieved in the messengers; plural.
How many messenger have the people of Nuh(نوح) received?
One.
How come Allahسُبحانه وتعالى said; it 's plural, you disbelieved in Al-Mursaleen(المرسلين); the messengers.
Because disbelieving in Nuh(نوح) is equivalent to disbelieving in all of the Ambiyaa(أنبِيَاء) of Allah.
And the same thing Allah said;
كَذَّبَتْ عَادٌ الْمُرْسَلِينَ۝
The people of Aad(عاد) disbelieved in the messengers, and they only received Hud(هود).
كَذَّبَتْ ثَمُودُ الْمُرْسَلِينَ۝
The people of Thamood(ثمود); they disbelieved in the messengers, and they received only Saleh(صالح).
كَذَّبَتْ قَوْمُ لُوطٍ الْمُرْسَلِينَ۝
The people of Lut(لوط) disbelieved in the messengers, and they only received Lutعليه السّلام.
Therefore, disbelieving in one of the Ambiyaa(أنبِيَاء) of Allahسُبحانه وتعالى is equal to disbelieving in all of them.
And this needs to be kept in mind, when we are talking about Al-Yahood(اليهود) and Nasara(نصارى), for example; the Jews and the Christians,
I mean; it's not up to you to make a choice of, who you want to follow and who you don't.
All of them are Ambiyaa(أنبِيَاء) of Allahسُبحانه وتعالى.
So the Jews; they have became non believers as soon as they rejected Jesus; Eesa(عيسى).
And the Nasara(نصارى); the followers of Jesus became disbelievers, the moment they disbelieved in Muhammadﷺ.
So following all of the Ambiyaa(أنبِيَاء); Allahسُبحانه وتعالى Is saying about the believers;
آمَنَ الرَّسُولُ بِمَا أُنزِلَ إِلَيْهِ مِن رَّبِّهِ وَالْمُؤْمِنُونَ ۚ كُلٌّ آمَنَ بِاللَّهِ وَمَلَائِكَتِهِ وَكُتُبِهِ وَرُسُلِهِ لَا نُفَرِّقُ بَيْنَ أَحَدٍ مِّن رُّسُلِهِ ۚ
Allahسُبحانه وتعالى says about the believers;
The messenger of Allah Has believed, and the believers have believed in him, in Allah,  and His messengers.
And Allahسُبحانه وتعالى says;
لَا نُفَرِّقُ بَيْنَ أَحَدٍ مِّن رُّسُلِهِ ۚ
They said; we do not make any distinction between any one of the messengers.
As Ummah(امة) of Muhammadﷺ; we don't make any distinction between them; we accept them all, as messengers of Allahسُبحانه وتعالى.
Finally, some of the unique characteristics of the Ambiyaa(أنبِيَاء).
The Ambiyaa(أنبِيَاء) of Allahسُبحانه وتعالى are Bashar(بشر); they're human beings.
They're human beings; but they have some unique qualities, which makes them different; unique.
Number one; Al-Wahi(ال-وحى); revelation.
They received Wahi(وحى) from Allahسُبحانه وتعالى; they received revelation.
That's the first unique quality of the Ambiyaa(أنبِيَاء).
Number two; the Ambiyaa(أنبِيَاء) of Allahسُبحانه وتعالى; they do not sleep as we do.
Their eyes sleep but their hearts don't.
Rasool Allah ﷺ says in the Hadith(حديث) narrated by Al Bukhari(البخاريْ);
وكذلك الأنبياء تنام ‏‏‏‏أعينهم ولا تنام قلوبهم
Rasool Allah ﷺ says in the Hadith(حديث) narrated by Al Bukhari(البخاريْ); .
The Ambiyaa(أنبِيَاء) of Allahسُبحانه وتعالى; their eye is sleep but their hearts don't.
And by the way, when you say; they don't sleep; their hearts are always awake.
They're carrying so much responsibility, and they have so much concern, and they're so attached to Allahسُبحانه وتعالى that the heart cannot sleep.
And the heart is always attached with Allahسُبحانه وتعالى.
Number three; Al-Ismah(العصمة); infallibility.
The Ambiyaa(أنبِيَاء) of Allahسُبحانه وتعالى; it is agreed upon, among the scholars of Islam.
That the Ambiyaa(أنبِيَاء) of Allahسُبحانه وتعالى never commit major sins.
They never commit major sins.
And it's also Ijma'(اجماع) of the Muslims, that the Ambiyaa(أنبِيَاء) of Allahسُبحانه وتعالى never committed a sin in conveying the message.
So they would never conceal knowledge for example;
they would never betray the trust;
they would never break a promise;
they would never lie.
And this is the consensus of all of the Ulama(عُلَمَا).
In terms of mistakes; various small minor sins; it is the opinion of the majority of the Ummah(امة) that the Ambiyaa(أنبِيَاء) could commit mistakes.
But, Allahسُبحانه وتعالى doesn't leave them on notice but Allah corrects them during their life.
So that, when they pass away; they leave us a message that is completely hundred percent pure.
There is no mistakes in it.
So when Sayidina Dawoodعليه السلام made a mistake in the judgment; Allahسُبحانه وتعالى corrected him.
So Allahسُبحانه وتعالى does not leave the messengers without teaching them, the right Ijtihaad(اجتهاد).
Therefore, whatever the Ambiyaa(أنبِيَاء) leave us; is hundred percent pure, infallible without any mistakes.
And that is called Al-Ismah(العصمة); Ismat-ul-Ambiyaa(العصمة الأنبِيَاء); the infallibility of the prophets.
The fourth quality which is unique about the Ambiyaa(أنبِيَاء) of Allahسُبحانه وتعالى; their soul is never taken until, till they give permission.
For us; our death is unannounced.
The Angel of Death, when he comes to you; he's not going to seek your permission, he's not going to knock on your door and say, can you please allow me in.
He's going to come, take it whether you like it or not.
With the Ambiyaa(أنبِيَاء) of Allahسُبحانه وتعالى; the Angel of Death comes to them, and seeks their permission first,
and tells them that, I have came to take your soul.
Rasool Allah ﷺ says in the Hadith(حديث);
ما من نبي يمرض إلا خير بين الدنيا والآخرة
Rasool Allah ﷺ says; Any prophet who becomes ill; and this is the illness of death.
Any prophet who becomes ill; he is given the choice of Duniyah(دُنِيَّا) or Akhirah(آخرة).
They choose.
And this Hadith(حديث) is narrated by Al Bukhari Wa Mulim(البخاريْ ومسلم).
Number five;
يقبر حيث يموت
Every prophet is buried exactly the spot they die.
They're not carried from one place to another.
Rasool Allah ﷺ says;
لن يُقبَرَ نبيٌّ إلَّا حيثُ يموتُ
Narrated by Al Imam Ahmad(الاِمَامْ اَحْمَدْ), Rasool Allah ﷺ says;
Every prophet is buried in the spot they die.
Number six;
The earth does not decompose their bodies, and eat away their bodies.
The bodies of the Ambiyaa(أنبِيَاء) are protected in their graves.
And the animals, and the insects of the earth, and the erosion caused by earth, does not affect their bodies.
Rasool Allah ﷺ says in the Hadith(حديث) narrated by Abu Daud Wan-Nisai(أبوداؤد والنّسائى) and Abu Khuzaimah(ابو خزيمه) has said, it is Sahih(صحيح);
إنَّ اللهَ حرَّم على الأرضِ أن تأكلَ أجسادَ الأنبياءِ
Allah Has made it Haram(حرام) on the earth to eat away from the bodies of the Ambiyaa(أنبِيَاء).
The body of the Nabi(نَبِي) is just like, when he was alive.
It does not go through the natural process of decomposing that we are susceptible to.
The Ambiyaa(أنبِيَاء) of  Allahسُبحانه وتعالى; Allah as an honoring for them; preserves their bodies in their graves, wherever they are.
Finally, number seven;
They are alive in their graves.
Rasool Allah ﷺ says in the Hadith(حديث) narrated by Al-Jama'ah(الجماعة);
الأنبياء أحياء في قبورهم يصلون
Rasool Allah ﷺ says; The prophets are alive in their graves and praying.
We're done with the lives of the Ambiyaa(أنبِيَاء) of Allahسُبحانه وتعالى.
And Allahسُبحانه وتعالى Has made for us in the lives of the Ambiyaa(أنبِيَاء) of Allahسُبحانه وتعالى Ibrah(عبرة).
And again, we need to remember what is the purpose of these stories?
It is;
لَقَدْ كَانَ فِي قَصَصِهِمْ عِبْرَةٌ
Allahسُبحانه وتعالى says; In their stories are lessons; Ibrah(عبرة); lessons for you.
We ask Allahسُبحانه وتعالى to make us of those, who would follow the lessons of the Ambiyaa(أنبِيَاء) of Allahسُبحانه وتعالى.
We ask Allahسُبحانه وتعالى to accept our deeds of coming here, and talking about of Ambiyaa(أنبِيَاء) of Allahسُبحانه وتعالى.
And we ask Allahسُبحانه وتعالى to make us of those, who would love the Ambiyaa(أنبِيَاء) of Allahسُبحانه وتعالى
because; if we love them; we will be resurrected with them on the day of judgment.
ونسئلك ان تجعلنا ممن يحب انبياءك
We ask Allahسُبحانه وتعالى to make us of those who love, deeply love, sincerely love the Ambiyaa(أنبِيَاء) of Allahسُبحانه وتعالى.